From Idaho Capitol Sun Trump
signs order seeking to curb vote
by mail in bid to control state
election laws Trump signs order
seeking to curb vote by mail in
bid to control state election
laws Trump's order represents
major escalation in effort to
assert presidential control over
elections which under the U S
Constitution are administered by
the states By Jonathan Shorman
April 1 2026 936 AM A mail
ballot drop box is seen at a
polling station on November 4
2025 in Arlington Virginia Photo
by Alex Wong A mail ballot drop
box is seen at a polling station
on November 4 2025 in Arlington
Virginia Photo by Alex Wong
Getty Images President Donald
Trump signed a sweeping
executive order on Tuesday that
attempts to restrict mail in
voting a White House priority
certain to face significant
legal challenges Trump's order
represents a major escalation in
his effort to assert
presidential control over
elections which under the U S
Constitution are administered by
the states Trump last year
attempted to unilaterally impose
a proof of citizenship
requirement to vote in federal
elections in an executive order
that was blocked in federal
court The move also reflects a
long held focus by Trump and his
allies on non citizen voters
Studies have shown non citizen
voting is extremely rare I think
this will help a lot with
elections Trump said National
Database of Adult Citizens The U
S Department of Justice as
recently as last week denied any
efforts to create a national
voter registration list While
the executive order does not
explicitly mandate the creation
of a voter list it essentially
marks an effort by the White
House to create a national
database of adult U S citizens
The order requires Homeland
Security to enable states to
routinely supplement or suggest
changes to each state's
citizenship list Federal
officials would also be required
to 7 010 more characters
truncated